<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blogging on Fernando Correia&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://fernandocorreia.dev/tags/blogging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blogging on Fernando Correia&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020, Fernando de Alcantara Correia; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 17:24:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fernandocorreia.dev/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Registering a website with Google Search Console</title>
      <link>https://fernandocorreia.dev/posts/google-search-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 17:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fernandocorreia.dev/posts/google-search-console/</guid>
      <description>Google has a free tool called Search Console that &amp;ldquo;help you measure your site&amp;rsquo;s Search traffic and performance, fix issues, and make your site shine in Google Search results&amp;rdquo;.
This is super handy to make sure that your website is being properly indexed by Google, to keep on top of how much traffic it is getting, and to be on the lookout for errors.
Registering your website with Google It only takes a few simple steps to add your website to Google&amp;rsquo;s Search Console:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom domain with GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://fernandocorreia.dev/posts/github-pages-custom-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 04:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fernandocorreia.dev/posts/github-pages-custom-domain/</guid>
      <description>I am hosting my blog on GitHub Pages. I wanted to use my own domain name instead of a github.io subdomain.
GitHub&amp;rsquo;s documentation is very helpful. Even so, it took me some effort to figure out all the details, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to share what I learned.
These instructions are for using an &amp;ldquo;apex domain&amp;rdquo; e.g. fernandocorreia.dev. The settings are a bit different when using a subdomain like www.fernandocorreia.dev. Again, GitHub&amp;rsquo;s documentation is very helpful and does a good job of explaining these differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog</title>
      <link>https://fernandocorreia.dev/posts/new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 21:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fernandocorreia.dev/posts/new-blog/</guid>
      <description>I decided to start a new blog to talk about software development.
It&amp;rsquo;s been about 5 years since I last had a blog, so I went looking for what people are using in 2020.
It turns out that Hugo is quite popular for building static sites.
Two of its selling points are that it is super fast, and that people have built hundreds of good-looking themes so that you can hit the ground running.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>